A Guide to the Francis X. (Frank) Sutton papers FA1141
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation, 1936-2012; 2; 24.02 Cubic Feet 51 legal document boxes
  - "Nation-Building: Social Transformation and Cultural Unity", undated (Box 32, Folder 278)
  - "The Ford Foundation and U.S. Higher Education", 1996 (Box 33, Folder 279)
  - "The Ford Foundation in Turkey" Draft, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 280)
  - "Purposes, Styles, and Performance in the First Years", undated (Box 33, Folder 281)
  - "The Foundation in International Affairs" or "Peace, Freedom, and International Order", 1988-1992 (Box 33, Folder 282)
  - "Africa, Latin America and Regional Approaches", undated (Box 33, Folder 283)
  - "International Philanthropy in a Large Foundation", undated (Box 33, Folder 284)
  - Drafts of Nepal Paper, 1990-1998 (Box 33, Folder 285)
  - "International Exchanges and Scholarly Research", 1989 (Box 33, Folder 286)
  - "Leaders for a World Power - Especially Lawyers", 1989 (Box 33, Folder 287)
  - Introduction for the Re-Issue of Dwight MacDonald's "The Ford Foundation", undated (Box 33, Folder 288)
  - "A Foundation Perspective on African Science", 1988 (Box 33, Folder 289)
  - "Ambitions, Constraints, and Strategies in the Making of a Foundation Program", 1991-1998 (Box 33, Folder 290)
  - "The Ford Foundation and Europe: Ambitions and Ambivalences", 1996 (Box 33, Folder 291)
  - "Problems and Strategy of Research in Less Developed Countries," Overseas Development Program, 1960 (Box 33, Folder 292)
  - "The Ford Foundation and Development in Tanzania", 1970 (Box 33, Folder 293)
  - "Larger Foundations and Non-Western Countries", 1962 (Box 33, Folder 294)
  - "Current American Research in the Social Sciences," Behavioral Sciences Program, 1956 (Box 34, Folder 295)
  - East - West Conference, Honolulu, 1985 February 18-22 (Box 34, Folder 296)
  - NAFSA Conference on Educational Exchange, Baltimore, 1985 May (Box 34, Folder 297)
  - Associated Colleges of the Midwest Conference, 1984 October 18-20 (Box 34, Folder 298)
  - The Influence of American Education in the Commonwealth, University of London Seminar, 1983 March 8 (Box 34, Folder 299)
  - American Council on Education (ACE) - Commission on International Education, 1981-1984 (Box 34, Folder 300-303)
  - African Studies Association, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 304)
  - Association for Asian Studies, 1984-1985 (Box 34, Folder 305)
  - Association of American Universities (AAU) Survey: International Studies, 1983 (Box 34, Folder 306)
  - Columbia Seminar on Philanthropy, 1985 (Box 34, Folder 307)
  - East European Publishing, 1984-1985 (Box 34, Folder 308)
  - Fondation pur une Entraide Intellectuelle Europeenne, 1985 (Box 34, Folder 309)
  - IBRD / Gittinger, 1983 (Box 34, Folder 310)
  - Fulbright Scholar Program - Research/Evaluation, 1983-1984 (Box 34, Folder 311)
  - International Educational Relations Project, University of Maryland, 1984 September 30-October 2 (Box 34, Folder 312)
  - JOSPOD Meeting, Harvard, 1985 February (Box 35, Folder 313)
  - MacArthur Foundation, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 314)
  - Smithsonian Symposium, 1983 December (Box 35, Folder 315)
  - Institute of International Education (IIE), 1981-1984 (Box 35, Folder 316)
  - UCLA, 1983-1984 (Box 35, Folder 317)
  - UCLA - African Studies Center Colloquium, 1967-1968 (Box 35, Folder 318)
  - Canadian Political Science Association - Annual Meeting, Ottawa, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 319)
  - International Conference on Education, Williamsburg Virginia, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 320)
  - Salt Lake City and Seattle Committees on Foreign Relations - East Africa Talk, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 321)
  - Planned Parenthood/Schenectady, 1969 May (Box 35, Folder 322)
  - "The International Role of the University in the Decades Ahead", 1973 (Box 35, Folder 323)
  - Council on Foreign Relations (CFR) Discussion Group on African Development, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 324)
  - "The Importance of Higher Education to Development," University of Minnesota, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 325)
  - "The Foundation and Less Developed Countries: The Decade of the Seventies", 1971 (Box 35, Folder 326)
  - Operation JANUS - Tanzania, Kenya, Other Countries, and Replies, undated (Box 35, Folder 327)
  - Funding for International Education, Columbia, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 328)
  - Overseas Development, 1962-1987 (Box 35, Folder 329)
  - International Training and Research Program (ITR), 1989-2000 (Box 36, Folder 330)
  - Yale Gallery, 1995 (Box 36, Folder 331)
  - USAID African Capacity in Economic Management, 1990 (Box 36, Folder 332)
  - Board of Foreign Scholarships (BFS) Meeting, Washington D.C., 1990 (Box 36, Folder 333)
  - Harvard Institute for International Development, 1983-1985 (Box 36, Folder 334)
    Grant for Aga Khan project.
  - Bard College International Academy for Scholarship and the Arts, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 335)
  - Education - Egypt, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 336)
  - MacArthur/Carnegie Group on International Security - Bundy, 1984 (Box 36, Folder 337)
  - "The Foundation's Work with Foreign Governments", 1971 (Box 36, Folder 338)
  - Law - International Programs, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 339-340)
  - Journees Braudeliennes Conference, Binghamton University, 1999 (Box 37, Folder 341)
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 342)
  - CIES Conference, San Diego, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 343)
  - MIT Seminar, "Science, Technology, and Society", 1981 (Box 37, Folder 344)
  - Sarah Lawrence Panel - Alice Ilchman Inauguration, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 345)
  - Kettering Foundation, Dayton Trip, 1981 November (Box 37, Folder 346)
  - American Council on Education (ACE) Annual Meeting, Washington, D.C., 1981 October (Box 37, Folder 347)
  - American Council on Education (ACE) Overseas Liaison Committee, Keynote Speech, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 348)
  - American Association for Advancement of Science (AAAS) Articles for Publication, 1981-1982 (Box 37, Folder 349)
  - International Encyclopedia of Education - Articles and Papers, 1965-1983 (Box 37, Folder 350)
  - Policy Notes, 1963-1980 (Box 37, Folder 351)
  - Foreign Graduate Students, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 352)
  - "Internationalizing Higher Education: A United States Approach", 1974 (Box 38, Folder 353)
  - "The Role of Foundations in Development," Texas A&M University, 1980 (Box 38, Folder 354)
  - "International Education for the Sub-Committee on International Operations: Comments, U.S. House of Representatives", 1978 (Box 38, Folder 355)
  - Brookings Symposium, "Africa: Challenges for American Philanthropy", 1978 (Box 38, Folder 356)
  - Human Rights Workshop, Aspen, 1977 (Box 38, Folder 357)
  - Eastern Sociological Society Annual Meeting, 1977 (Box 38, Folder 358)
  - International Council for Educational Development, Aspen, 1976 (Box 38, Folder 359)
  - American Political Science Association Annual Meeting, "The Foundations and the Governments of Developing Countries", 1976 (Box 38, Folder 360)
  - Conference on Funding International Education, Columbia University, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 361)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1978 (Box 38, Folder 362)
  - Conference on Social Sciences in the Middle East, 1974 (Box 38, Folder 363)
  - "Black Africa in 1973", undated (Box 38, Folder 364)
  - History of the Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research (CGIAR), 1986 (Box 38, Folder 365)
  - Council on Foreign Relations (CFR) - Review Panel on Research and Studies Program, 1972-1973 (Box 38, Folder 366)
  - Council on Foreign Relations (CFR) - Evaluation, 1973 (Box 39, Folder 367-368)
  - Cultural Development, 1967-1968 (Box 39, Folder 369)
  - Intellectuals and Ideology, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 370)
  - Arts Paper, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 371)
  - Literature, Criticism, and Culture, 1963-1978 (Box 39, Folder 372)
  - Age, Sex, and Dress, 1952 (Box 39, Folder 373)
  - UNESCO Chronicle, 1976 (Box 40, Folder 374)
  - Turnpikes and Technology, 1968-1983 (Box 40, Folder 375)
  - Process of Rationalization, 1952-1955 (Box 40, Folder 376)
  - History of Earth, 1980 (Box 40, Folder 377)
  - Comparative Politics, 1963 (Box 40, Folder 378)
  - Universities, 1963-1971 (Box 40, Folder 379)
  - Universities and Development, 1967-1968 (Box 40, Folder 380)
  - Development - Notes and Writings, 1964 (Box 40, Folder 381)
  - Employment - Notes and Ideas, 1973-1974 (Box 40, Folder 382)
  - Rockefeller Foundation and Development, 1981-1985 (Box 40, Folder 383)
  - Miscellaneous Papers of Relevance, 1983-1985 (Box 40, Folder 384)
    Papers by Kathleen D. McCarthy, Robert L. Payton, and Kenneth Prewitt.
  - Rural Development, 1967-1983 (Box 40, Folder 385)
  - Politics, 1950 (Box 40, Folder 386)
  - Government - Colonial to Independent, 1967 (Box 41, Folder 387)
  - Technical Assistance, 1965-1969 (Box 41, Folder 388)
  - Five Year Budget Projection, 1973-1977 (Box 41, Folder 389)
  - Religion, 1976 (Box 41, Folder 390)
  - Population, 1975-1976 (Box 41, Folder 391-392)
  - Ford/SSRC Joint Committee for Latin American Studies, 1974 (Box 41, Folder 393)
  - Ford/SSRC Joint Committee on African Studies, 1983-1992 (Box 41, Folder 394)
  - Agriculture, 1980-1991 (Box 42, Folder 395)
  - Higher Education, 2001-2005 (Box 42, Folder 396)
  - Philanthropy, 2006 (Box 42, Folder 397)
  - The Ford Foundation, United Nations, and Peace, 1995 (Box 42, Folder 398)
  - FAFP, SSRC, and the Ford Foundation, 1970 (Box 42, Folder 399)
  - Tax-Exempt Foundations, Pendleton Herring, 1954 (Box 42, Folder 400)
  - Social Science Engagements, 1955-1959 (Box 42, Folder 401)
  - Reece - ESS, 1954 (Box 42, Folder 402)
  - Ford Foundation and African Studies - Sutton/Smock, undated (Box 42, Folder 403)
  - Chicago Conference on Social Implications of Industrialization, 1960 (Box 42, Folder 404)
  - Center for Human Sciences, Paris, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 405)
  - Australia - International Exchanges and Scholarly Research, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 406)
  - Australia - Fulbright Grantees, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 407)
    - Australia 9/23, 2013:053:010
  - International Affairs, 1959-1977 (Box 43, Folder 408)
  - Africa, 1977-2011 (Box 43, Folder 409-411)
  - Africa - Memoranda, 1958 (Box 43, Folder 412)
  - Africa - MIT, 1963-1964 (Box 43, Folder 413)
  - East Africa and JANUS, 1961-1965 (Box 43, Folder 414)
  - French Africa, 1957-1961 (Box 44, Folder 415)
  - North Africa, 1972-1999 (Box 44, Folder 416)
  - African Science, Bellagio, 1988 (Box 44, Folder 417)
  - Asia, 1973-1998 (Box 44, Folder 418-420)
  - Southeast Asia, 1950-1998 (Box 45, Folder 421-422)
  - Botswana, 1981-1999 (Box 45, Folder 423)
  - China, 1954-1970 (Box 45, Folder 424)
  - Europe, 1968-1996 (Box 45, Folder 425-426)
  - Eastern Europe, 1972-1973 (Box 45, Folder 427)
  - Eastern Europe and USSR, 1968-1999 (Box 46, Folder 428)
  - Egypt, 1988-1989 (Box 46, Folder 429)
  - Ghana, 1961 (Box 46, Folder 430)
  - Hawaii, 1982 (Box 46, Folder 431)
    Includes speech "International Cooperation in Higher Education, Scholarship and Research"
  - India, 1954-1973 (Box 46, Folder 432-433)
  - India - Ensminger, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 434)
  - Indonesia, 1958-1992 (Box 47, Folder 435-436)
    This file (despite it's original title "Indonesia") also contains a Ford Foundation report on Iran called, "The Formation and Development of the Economic Bureau of Plan Organization in Iran."
  - Indonesia - Economics, 1955-1957 (Box 47, Folder 437)
  - Indonesia - John Bresnan, 2005 (Box 47, Folder 438-439)
  - Iran, 1964 (Box 47, Folder 440)
  - Reflections on Japan Visit, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 441)
  - Japan and East Asian Studies, 1975-1978 (Box 47, Folder 442)
  - Kenya, 1963 (Box 48, Folder 443)
  - Latin America, 1974-1976 (Box 48, Folder 444)
  - Mexico, 1966-1999 (Box 48, Folder 445)
  - Middle East, 1956-1966 (Box 48, Folder 446-448)
  - Middle East, Africa, Asia, 1957-1999 (Box 49, Folder 449-451)
  - Middle East and North Africa, 1952-1971 (Box 49, Folder 452)
  - Middle East and Pakistan, 1985-1986 (Box 49, Folder 453)
  - Nepal, 1985 (Box 49, Folder 454)
  - Pakistan, 1930-2004 (Box 49, Folder 455)
  - Rhodesia, 1955-1956 (Box 49, Folder 456)
  - Russia, 1960-2000 (Box 50, Folder 457)
  - Turkey, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 458)
  - Vietnam, 1969-1976 (Box 50, Folder 459-460)
  - Country Reports, undated (Box 50, Folder 461)
    Egypt, Iran, Iraq, Jordan, Saudi Arabia, Syria, and Turkey.
  - Foundations Lecture, 1960-1967 (Box 50, Folder 462)
  - Language Development, 1967-1976 (Box 50, Folder 463)
  - Human Rights, 1986-1992 (Box 50, Folder 464)
  - Cultural Freedom, 1959-2009 (Box 50, Folder 465-466)
  - David E. Bell, 2000 (Box 51, Folder 467)
  - McGeorge Bundy, 1962-2008 (Box 51, Folder 468-469)
  - McGeorge Bundy Dinner, 1979 (Box 51, Folder 470)
  - Frederick H. Burkhardt, 2005-2008 (Box 51, Folder 471)
  - Robert H. Edwards, 2000-2005 (Box 51, Folder 472)
  - Herbert Erf, Jr., 1973 (Box 51, Folder 473)
  - Wilbur "Ping" Ferry, 1995 (Box 51, Folder 474)
  - Rowan Gaither, 1992 (Box 51, Folder 475)
  - Henry Townley Heald, 1995 (Box 51, Folder 476)
  - John Howard, 1999-2000 (Box 51, Folder 477)
  - Peter de Janosi, 2011 (Box 51, Folder 478)
  - Charles W. Maynes, 2007-2008 (Box 52, Folder 479)
  - Waldemar Nielsen, 2006-2007 (Box 52, Folder 480)
  - Joseph Elliot Slater, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 481)
  - Howard Swearer, 1998 (Box 52, Folder 482)
  - Franklin Thomas, 1980-1982 (Box 52, Folder 483)
  - F. Champion Ward, 2007 (Box 52, Folder 484)
  - F. Champion Ward - Andrew Abbott, 1995-2004 (Box 52, Folder 485)
  - Herman B. Wells, 2000 (Box 52, Folder 486)
  - Memorial Service Programs, 1986-1990 (Box 52, Folder 487)
    Soedjatmoko (Asia Society), Charles E. Wyzanski, Jr.
  - "The Ford Foundation: The Men and the Millions," Dwight MacDonald (Introduction by Francis X. Sutton), 1987-1989 (Box 53, Folder 488)
  - "The Ford Foundation's Transatlantic Roles and Purposes, 1951-1981," Binghamton Conference, 1999 (Box 53, Folder 489)
  - "Foundations and Higher Education at Home and Abroad: A Tale of Heroic Efforts Abandoned", 1987 (Box 53, Folder 490)
  - "The Ford Foundation: A Ten-Year Summary", 1951-1960 (Box 53, Folder 491)
  - "The Ford Foundation: The Formative Years," William Greenleaf, 1986 (Box 53, Folder 492-493)
  - "The American-Yugoslav Project in Urban and Regional Planning," Urban History Chapter VII, 1989 (Box 54, Folder 494)
  - "The Athens Center of Ekistics," Urban History Chapter VII, 1989 (Box 54, Folder 495)
  - "An Annotated Bibliography on the History of American Foundations," Kathleen D. McCarthy, 1986 (Box 54, Folder 496-498)
  - "The Ford Foundation: Management and Program Trends in the Fifties and Sixties", 1971 (Box 54, Folder 499)
  - "The Foundation and Public Management in the Less-Developed Countries", 1975 (Box 54, Folder 500)
  - "The Foundation and the Less Developed Countries: The Decade of the Seventies," Ford Foundation Staff Working Paper, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 501)
  - "OD Self-Study," Ford Foundation Information Paper, 1966 (Box 55, Folder 502)
  - "Capacity Building for Policy Analysis Lessons of Experience", undated (Box 55, Folder 503)
  - "International Human Rights Information and Documentation Service," Ford Foundation Information Paper, 1979 (Box 55, Folder 504)
  - "Human Rights and Intellectual Freedom," Ford Foundation Information Paper, 1975 (Box 55, Folder 505)
  - "Human Rights, Freedom, and the Liberal Tradition", 1976 (Box 55, Folder 506)
  - "International Organization and Law", 1989 (Box 55, Folder 507)
  - "International Philanthropy in a Large Foundation", undated (Box 55, Folder 508)
  - "International Liaison of Universities," Keynote Address to the American Council on Education, 1979 (Box 55, Folder 509)
  - "Refugees and Mass Exoduses: The Search for a Human Effective Policy", 1986 (Box 55, Folder 510)
  - International Education, 1974-1985 (Box 55, Folder 511)
  - International Education Articles and Reprints, 1960-1965 (Box 56, Folder 512)
  - International Training and Research Program Grants, 1951-1998 (Box 56, Folder 513-514)
  - "Evaluation in the International Division", 1975 (Box 56, Folder 515-516, Box 57, Folder 517)
  - "The Ford Foundation's Population Programs in India, Pakistan and Bangladesh", 1959-1981 (Box 57, Folder 518)
  - "Research and Training on Asia," Office for Asia and the Pacific, 1969 (Box 57, Folder 519)
  - International Affairs - Goodwin paper, 1988 (Box 57, Folder 520-521)
  - CIA Relations, 1952-1958 (Box 57, Folder 522)
  - Program Reviews, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 523)
  - Studies of Ford Foundation Programs, 1977-1987 (Box 58, Folder 524-528)
    Topics include business, contraception, Myers on education abroad, Harvard Institute for International Development, Hutchins College, and India.
  - Gannon and Ashizawa, 1995-2002 (Box 58, Folder 529)
  - Columbia University, 1966-1999 (Box 59, Folder 530)
  - Northwestern University, 1962-1963 (Box 59, Folder 531)
  - Urban Strategies, 2000 (Box 59, Folder 532)
  - Behavioral Science, 1954-1955 (Box 59, Folder 533)
  - Bloody Tanistry - Fletcher, 1978 (Box 59, Folder 534)
  - Schenectady Talk - Populations and Education, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 535)
  - Developmental Studies, 1972-1973 (Box 59, Folder 536)
  - "Ford Foundation Activities in the Creative and Performing Arts Theater", 1957-1979 (Box 59, Folder 537)
  - "The Arts and Culture in the Ford Foundation", 1981 (Box 59, Folder 538)
  - American Business Creed, undated (Box 60, Folder 539)
  - "Volume I of Papers Prepared for Pakistan Review", 1969 (Box 60, Folder 540)
  - "Volume II of Papers Prepared for Pakistan Review", 1969 (Box 60, Folder 541)
  - "The Ford Foundation Program in Pakistan", 1970 (Box 60, Folder 542)
  - "The Ford Foundation in India and Pakistan", 1952-1970 (Box 60, Folder 543)
  - Economic Development, 1958-1980 (Box 60, Folder 544)
  - Foreign Affairs Committee, 1968 (Box 60, Folder 545)
  - "The Foundation's Current Strategy in the Support of International Studies", 1967 (Box 61, Folder 546)
  - "International Migration and Refugees", 1980 (Box 61, Folder 547)
  - "Planning for the Foundation's Activities in Europe", 1967 (Box 61, Folder 548)
  - "The Foundation's Program Concerned with the World Economy", 1980 (Box 61, Folder 549)
  - "Support of International Studies in American Universities", 1969 (Box 61, Folder 550)
  - Report on Overseas Compensation Review, 1980 (Box 61, Folder 551)
  - "The Rockefeller-Ford International Agricultural Research Institutes", 1967 (Box 61, Folder 552)
  - "Europe and the United States in a Changing World", 1973 (Box 61, Folder 553)
  - International Division Summary Tables, 1973-1981 (Box 61, Folder 554-558, Box 62, Folder 559-562)
  - Developing Country Program Summary Tables, 1982-1988 (Box 62, Folder 563-568)
  - Evaluation Studies, 1963-1975 (Box 63, Folder 569-573)
  - European University, 1958 (Box 63, Folder 574)
  - Role of Government in Development, 1991 (Box 64, Folder 575)
  - Nuclear Research, 1955-1961 (Box 64, Folder 576)
  - Conditions of Peace Project, 1951-1953 (Box 64, Folder 577)
  - International Affairs Grants, 1961-1984 (Box 64, Folder 578-580)
  - International Development, 1987-1988 (Box 65, Folder 581-583)
  - Docket - Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1983 (Box 65, Folder 584)
  - Sailer and Law, 1969-1986 (Box 65, Folder 585)
  - Law, 1967-1984 (Box 66, Folder 586-587)
  - "The International Legal Center and Law in the Foundation's International Programs", 1971 (Box 66, Folder 588)
  - Lagemann Colloquium Paper, 1957-1997 (Box 66, Folder 589)
  - History of Education Meeting, Columbia University, 1987 (Box 66, Folder 590)
  - Technical Assistance Then and Now, New York University, 1997 (Box 66, Folder 591)
  - Economic Development Grants, 1997 (Box 67, Folder 592)
  - "American Foundations in Non-Western Areas", 1962-1963 (Box 67, Folder 593)
  - "Authority and Authoritarians in the New Africa", 1961-1962 (Box 67, Folder 594)
  - Wildcat Applicant Case Studies, 1960 (Box 67, Folder 595)
  - "Education in Changing Africa," Journal of Human Relations, 1962 (Box 67, Folder 596-597)
  - "Social Theory and Comparative Politics", 1962-1963 (Box 67, Folder 598)
  - ISA Paper - "Fitness for Self - Government and Development in Modern Africa", 1960-1962 (Box 67, Folder 599)
  - International Affairs and Europe Papers, 1972-1989 (Box 67, Folder 600)
  - Bangladesh University, 1996-2001 (Box 67, Folder 601)
  - Urban Programs Overseas, 2000 (Box 67, Folder 602)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1970-1971 (Box 67, Folder 603)
  - MIT Center for International Studies, 2001-2002 (Box 67, Folder 604)
  - Africa and Contemporary Ideas, MIT, 1963 (Box 68, Folder 605)
  - Course - Business in America, Salzburg, 1956 (Box 68, Folder 606)
  - Theories of Political Development, MIT, 1963 (Box 68, Folder 607)
  - General Education, 1947-1953 (Box 68, Folder 608-609)
  - Harvard, 1946-1984 (Box 68, Folder 610)
  - Harvard Survey of the Behavioral Sciences, 1954 (Box 69, Folder 611)
  - Marxism, 1953-1954 (Box 69, Folder 612)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1954 (Box 69, Folder 613)
  - Social Sciences, 1995-2007 (Box 69, Folder 614)
  - Social Science Encyclopedia, 1962 (Box 69, Folder 615-616)
  - Science Outlines, 1956 (Box 69, Folder 617)
  - Nitze School of Advanced International Studies (SAIS) Paper, 2004-2005 (Box 69, Folder 618-619)
    Nation Building
  - Subcommittee Hearings on Africa House of Representatives, 1960-2010 (Box 70, Folder 620)
  - Foundations and International Organizations, 1984-1999 (Box 70, Folder 621)
  - IIC Survey Report - Final, 1996-1997 (Box 70, Folder 622)
  - International Higher Education, Yale Planning Meeting, 2000 (Box 70, Folder 623)
  - Cairo Office 50th Anniversary, 2007 (Box 70, Folder 624)
  - Giuliana Gemelli - Ford Foundation and Europe, 1993-1996 (Box 70, Folder 625)
  - Islam Clippings, 1992-2002 (Box 70, Folder 626)
  - Philanthropic Foundations in History, New York University, 1996 (Box 70, Folder 627)
  - CENIS and MIT Center for International Studies, 1951-1999 (Box 71, Folder 628)
  - Education in Developing Countries, 1982 (Box 71, Folder 629)
  - International Division - Management Budget Meetings, 1980-1981 (Box 71, Folder 630)
    Restricted from research - contains personnel information.
  - Draeger Publication, 1983-1984 (Box 71, Folder 631)
  - Gregorian - Carnegie Corporation, 1997-1998 (Box 71, Folder 632)
  - Jayanth Krishnan - Law, 1989-2011 (Box 71, Folder 633)
  - Language, 1985 (Box 71, Folder 634)
  - Governance, 1977-1979 (Box 71, Folder 635)
  - International Legal Studies, 1949-1964 (Box 71, Folder 636)
  - The 1956 Chapter, 1956-1959 (Box 72, Folder 637)
  - Foundation Papers, 1973 (Box 72, Folder 638)
  - Miscellaneous, 1966-1986 (Box 72, Folder 639-640)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, undated (Box 72, Folder 641)
  - Ford Foundation History Project, 1953-2010; 1
    - Background Material, 1953-2010 (Box 72, Folder 642-644)
    - Beylin Manuscript, 1991-1995 (Box 73, Folder 645)
    - Chronology, 1936-1979 (Box 73, Folder 646)
    - Correspondence, 2000-2005 (Box 73, Folder 647)
    - Digital Material (Box 73, Folder 647A)
    - Education Chapter, 1984 (Box 73, Folder 648)
    - Expense Reports, 1985 (Box 73, Folder 649)
    - Financial and Statistical Lists, 1982-1992 (Box 73, Folder 650)
    - Geographic Areas, 1984 (Box 73, Folder 651)
      Africa, Burma, Europe, India, Indonesia, Iran, Latin America, Middle East, Pakistan, and Southeast Asia.
    - National Integration, 1954-2010 (Box 74, Folder 652)
    - Outlines, 1985-2004 (Box 74, Folder 653-655)
    - Pakistan and Nepal Chapter, 1984 (Box 74, Folder 656)
    - Pakistan Revisions, 1998 (Box 74, Folder 657)
    - Plans and Publishing, 2002-2004 (Box 74, Folder 658)
    - Oral History Project, 1974 (Box 74, Folder 659)
    - Subject Files, 1984-1986 (Box 74, Folder 660)
    - Part I, 1951-2007 (Box 75, Folder 661-664)
    - Part II, 1951-2003 (Box 75, Folder 665-667, Box 76, Folder 668-670)